The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: I want to talk about two things,
教授：我想谈两件事，
maybe, depending on the level of interest.
也许，取决于兴趣程度。
We can talk a little bit about PSET five and the things
我们可以谈谈PSET 5及其它
that I think are weird in the coding part of PSET five.
我认为在PSET 5的编码部分中很奇怪。
By the way, how many people started PSET five?
顺便问一下，有多少人开始了PSET 5？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
AUDIENCE: I downloaded it.
听众：我下载了它。
PROFESSOR: Hmm, maybe we are not going to talk about P set five.
教授：嗯，也许我们不打算讨论P集5。
You guys need to start early!
你们需要早点开始！
AUDIENCE: I did.
听众：我做到了。
PROFESSOR: You did.
教授：是的。
Yeah.
是的
I guess I can't punish you for everyone else.
我想我不能为别人惩罚你。
So P set five, and I can talk about graphs.
因此，P设置了五个，我可以谈谈图。
I can talk about whatever didn't make sense in class
我可以说什么在课堂上没有意义的事情
and I can talk about background stuff for graphs.
我可以谈谈图形的背景知识。
So how do people feel?
那么人们感觉如何？
Who wants talk about the PSET that we haven't read?
谁想谈论我们尚未阅读的PSET？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Who wants to talk about graphs?
谁想谈论图？
AUDIENCE: It's really easy.
听众：真的很容易。
We took 604 two.
我们拿了604两。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, if you took 604 two, nothing here is new.
教授：是的，如果您拿了604两，那么这里没有什么新鲜的。
I mean nothing in the recitation is new.
我的意思是朗诵中没有什么是新的。
We're going to take it to new heights of graph knowledge,
我们将把它带到图形知识的新高度，
and you'll be able to do many more cool things
而且您将能够做更多更酷的事情
that you're able to do before.
您以前能够做到的。
OK, so PSET.
好的，所以是PSET。
For people who started early, what
对于早起的人
was the gist of the coding assignments?
是编码任务的要点？
AUDIENCE: So we have to speed up something.
听众：所以我们必须加快速度。
When I ran the tests-- do I say what I got as results?
当我运行测试时-我说我得到的结果是什么？
PROFESSOR: The time isn't on the PSET so you can say what you
教授：时间不在PSET上，所以您可以说出您的意思
got as --
作为-
AUDIENCE: Pardon?
听众：对不起？
PROFESSOR: The time isn't on the PSET
教授：时间不在PSET上
so you can say what you got as a time.
这样您就可以说出您的时间了。
AUDIENCE: OK, the slowest was like add for me.
听众：好的，最慢的就像给我加价。
PROFESSOR: You should look to see add is a valid answer.
教授：您应该看一下add是一个有效的答案。
Look at the questions and see if add is a valid answer.
查看问题，看看添加是否是有效答案。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: It's not like what was lowest function, right?
教授：这不是最低功能，对吗？
There's more text there.
那里还有更多文字。
You should read the rest of the text
您应该阅读其余的文字
and see if add makes sense as a valid answer.
并查看添加是否有效。
AUDIENCE: Sure.
听众：好的。
OK.
好。
PROFESSOR: What you're doing-- big picture--
教授：您在做什么-大图景-
is you have some processor, that's not a real processor,
你有处理器吗，那不是真正的处理器，
and it can do arithmetic with bytes and 16-bit words.
它可以使用字节和16位字进行算术运算。
And we give you the basic operations
我们为您提供基本操作
and then they give you a library for large number arithmetic
然后他们给你一个用于大量算术的库
because, guess what?
因为，你猜怎么着？
16 bytes addition, subtraction?
16字节加，减？
Not going to cut it for science applications
不会为科学应用削减它
are for cryptography, what we want to play with.
用于密码学，我们想玩的东西。
What are the basic operations that that processor can do?
该处理器可以执行的基本操作是什么？
Front of the PSET, so even if you
PSET的前面，所以即使您
didn't get to the coding assignment
没有去编码分配
you can still tell me.
你仍然可以告诉我。
AUDIENCE: Divide, and zeros, I think.
听众：我认为除以零。
Zeros.
零
PROFESSOR: Plus, minus, multiply, divide, and mod.
教授：加，减，乘，除和mod。
Let's start to these.
让我们开始这些。
So you have two primitives in that processor.
因此，该处理器中有两个原语。
You have have bytes, which are basically 8-bit digits.
您有字节，基本上是8位数字。
There's 200.
有200
The range is 0 to 256.
范围是0到256。
And the word is 16-bit, from 0 to the 16 minus 1.
字是16位，从0到16减1。
If you care to know this is 6, 5, 5, 3, 5.
如果您知道这是6、5、5、3、5。
So, if you take two bytes and add them together what do
因此，如果您占用两个字节并将它们加在一起，该怎么办
you get?
你得到？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Not right.
教授：不对。
It's a trick question.
这是一个技巧问题。
You get word.
你听懂了。
The processor cannot do simple math on bytes.
处理器无法对字节进行简单的数学运算。
It converts them up to words and all the math happens on words.
它将它们转换为单词，所有数学运算都在单词上进行。
Now if you guess two words, and add them up together
现在，如果您猜两个单词，并将它们加在一起
what do you get?
你得到了什么？
AUDIENCE: Two words?
听众：两个字？
PROFESSOR: You do if we're not that nice.
教授：如果我们不那么好，您可以这样做。
AUDIENCE: A world in carry bit?
听众：随身携带的世界吗？
PROFESSOR: Sorry, you just get word.
教授：对不起，您只是一句话而已。
At least nobody said a byte.
至少没有人说一个字节。
I was like, please don't say byte, please don't say byte.
我当时想，请不要说字节，请不要说字节。
You said carry bit.
你说进位。
Why do we care about the carry bit?
为什么我们在乎进位？
What is the problem if you do addition this way?
如果您以这种方式加法会出现什么问题？
AUDIENCE: If you're going too high.
听众：如果你太高了。
If the highest bit is one on both of them.
如果两者最高。
Then it's like overflow, kind of.
然后就像溢出一样。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Suppose we're trying to add 2 to the 16 minus 1 plus 2
假设我们尝试将16加2减1加2
to the 16 minus 1.
到16减1。
By the way, does anyone remember hex notation?
顺便说一句，有人记得十六进制符号吗？
Hexadecimal?
十六进制的？
OK, people who started the PSET remember.
好的，启动PSET的人记得。
That's good.
那很好。
It will be easy to write things hex for the PSET.
为PSET编写十六进制的内容很容易。
If you try to add these numbers you're going to get 1, F, F, F,
如果您尝试将这些数字相加，则会得到1，F，F，F，
E. You can use the math here to see
E.您可以在这里使用数学来查看
that this is more than the words.
这不仅仅是言语。
So you would like to know that this thing overflows, right?
所以你想知道这东西溢出了吧？
You like to know that there is.
您想知道那里。
Well we don't give you that.
好吧，我们不给你。
All you get to this.
所有你得到的。
So addition happens, modulo 2 to the 16.
所以加法发生了，模2等于16。
If you want to be able to detect overflow what they have to do?
如果您希望能够检测到溢出，他们该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Just tests those bits.
听众：只测试那些位。
PROFESSOR: That one way of doing it.
教授：这是一种方法。
It would take quite a few instructions, though.
但是，这将需要很多指令。
If you want to do overflow detection,
如果要进行溢出检测，
the easiest way I think of doing it this to use this form.
我想到的最简单的方法就是使用这种形式。
So suppose you have two bytes.
因此，假设您有两个字节。
This is the maximum value in a byte, right?
这是一个字节的最大值，对吗？
255, 2 to the 8 minus 1.
255，2到8减1。
If you have 2 bytes and you add them all together
如果您有2个字节，然后将它们全部加在一起
you're going to get 1, F, E. Right?
您将得到1，F，E。对吗？
It's just like the case here, except you have a fewer F's.
就像这里的情况一样，只不过您的F较少。
Where is the carry here?
提货在哪里？
AUDIENCE: Could be the 1, right?
听众：可以是1，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
This guy here is the carry and this guy's the low result.
这家伙是随身携带的，这家伙的成绩很低。
Does anyone know how these are called?
有人知道这些怎么称呼吗？
If you have a word and you have two bytes, what
如果您有一个单词并且有两个字节，那
is the first byte, what is the second bytes?
是第一个字节，第二个字节是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Most significant byte,
教授：最高有效字节，
M, S, B, and least significant byte,
M，S，B和最低有效字节，
L, S, B. If you want to figure out your carries,
L，S，B。如果您想弄清楚自己的携带方式，
then you should do your math this way.
那么您应该以这种方式进行数学计算。
You're going to have byte 1 plus byte 2.
您将拥有字节1和字节2。
Add them together.
将它们加在一起。
And then you call L, S, B to get the byte result.
然后调用L，S，B来获取字节结果。
And then you call M, S, B to get the carry.
然后您致电M，S，B进行进位。
This is addition.
这是加法。
Everyone with me so far?
到目前为止和我在一起的每个人？
By the way, are these numbers signed or unsigned?
顺便说一下，这些数字是带符号的还是无符号的？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: No negative numbers, right?
教授：没有负数，对吗？
So no support for negative numbers.
因此不支持负数。
Everything is going to be positive.
一切将是积极的。
And we're going to build everything
我们将建立一切
we need off of positive numbers because they're
我们需要正数，因为它们是
easier to deal with.
更容易处理。
What if I have two words and I subtract them?
如果我有两个单词并减去它们怎么办？
What do I get?
我能得到什么？
AUDIENCE: Word.
听众：字。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What if I have 0 minus 1?
如果我有0减去1怎么办？
What do I get?
我能得到什么？
AUDIENCE: 0.
听众：0。
PROFESSOR: Not quite.
教授：不完全是。
AUDIENCE: If you're not using signs?
听众：如果您不使用标志？
Do you get O, 1?
你得到O，1？
PROFESSOR: O, 1's, OK.
教授：O，1，好的。
AUDIENCE: Ya.
听众：是的。
Wait--
等待 -
PROFESSOR: So, O 1's would be this, F, F, F, F.
教授：所以，O 1是这个F，F，F，F。
AUDIENCE: That's assuming if you signed then.
听众：这是假设您是否已签署。
It will overflow.
它将溢出。
That's a really big number then.
那真是一个很大的数字。
PROFESSOR: So fancy CS, 2's complement.
教授：非常好的CS，2的补码。
For people who think in math mode, what is this?
对于以数学模式思考的人，这是什么？
AUDIENCE: I think.
听众：我认为。
PROFESSOR: It's minus 1 mod 2 to the 16.
教授：这是1模2减16模。
Remember, when we were doing modular arithmetic before,
请记住，当我们之前进行模块化算术时，
to figure out a number's multiplicative inverse?
找出数字的乘法逆数？
And when we were doing rolling hashes?
当我们做滚动哈希时？
We didn't want negative numbers.
我们不想要负数。
We made them positive.
我们使他们积极。
So minus 1 lot to the 16 is 2 to the 16.
所以16减去1手就是2等于16。
Minus 1, and comes out to this value.
减1，得出该值。
So you get minus 1, it's just that you
所以你得到负1，就是你
have to know your basis.
必须知道你的依据。
So we got the addition and subtraction.
这样我们得到了加法和减法。
Let's talk about multiplication.
让我们谈谈乘法。
What do you do for multiplication?
你做什么乘法？
What can you multiply?
你可以乘以什么？
Two bytes, very good.
两个字节，非常好。
Just two bytes.
只有两个字节。
What do you get?
你得到了什么？
A word.
一个字。
Thank you.
谢谢。
You multiply two bytes, you get a word.
您将两个字节相乘得到一个字。
What if there's overflow?
如果有溢出怎么办？
It's a trick question.
这是一个技巧问题。
AUDIENCE: There's no overflow.
听众：没有溢出。
PROFESSOR: There is no overflow.
教授：没有溢出。
So two bytes, 2 to the eighth minus 1 times 2
所以两个字节2到第八减1乘以2
to the eighth minus 1, is 2 to the 16 minus 2
到第八减1，是2到16减2
to the 8th minus 2 to the eighth plus 1.
到第八减2到第八加1。
You can say this safely without doing the arithmetic, right?
您可以不用算术就可以安全地说出来，对吗？
This is how much you can hold, in other words.
换句话说，这就是您可以持有的数量。
This is how much you can holding in a byte.
这是您可以容纳一个字节的数量。
AUDIENCE: Why do you minus 1?
听众：为什么要减去1？
PROFESSOR: Ya, minus 1.
教授：是的，负1。
There's a minus 1 here, and there's a minus 1 here,
这里是负1，这里是负1，
but I can't find it here, so roughly this.
但我在这里找不到它，大致如此。
But there is an overflow.
但是有一个溢出。
AUDIENCE: But where did you get the minus 1 from?
听众：但是，您从哪里得到负1？
PROFESSOR: Where do you get the-- so,
教授：您从哪里得到的-所以，
this is how much you can hold in a byte.
这是一个字节可以容纳的数量。
Byte has 8 bits, right?
字节有8位，对吗？
From 0 0 to F F. This is 2 to the eighth minus 1.
从0 0到FF。这是2到第八减1。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: OK, so multiplication?
教授：好的，乘法吗？
There is an overflow.
有一个溢出。
I don't have to deal with that.
我不必处理。
You guys have to figure out how to deal with it.
你们必须弄清楚如何处理它。
How about division?
师呢？
What can you divide?
你可以划分什么？
AUDIENCE: Some words?
听众：有些话吗？
PROFESSOR: Almost.
教授：差不多了。
AUDIENCE: Words like--
听众：像-
PROFESSOR: A word divided by a byte.
教授：一个字除以一个字节。
What do you get out of it?
你从中得到什么？
AUDIENCE: Words?
听众：话？
PROFESSOR: That would be nice.
教授：那很好。
Nope.
不。
Sorry, you get a byte.
抱歉，您得到一个字节。
And if you do module, you also get a byte.
如果执行模块，则还会得到一个字节。
What if there's overflow in the division?
如果部门有溢出怎么办？
What happens?
怎么了？
What would you expect to happen?
您期望发生什么？
AUDIENCE: We don't have any best flowing point numbers,
观众：我们没有最佳的流点数，
so, we shouldn't get overflow, right?
所以，我们不应该溢出，对不对？
PROFESSOR: How about 2 to the 16 minus 1 divided by 1?
教授：2到16减1除以1怎么样？
So what do get?
那么得到什么呢？
AUDIENCE: Same thing?
听众：同样吗？
PROFESSOR: Will this fit in the byte?
教授：这适合字节吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes?
听众：是吗？
No.
没有。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
No.
没有。
Well, that time I don't get a word.
好吧，那一次我一言不发。
PROFESSOR: You don't get a word.
教授：您一言不发。
I promise you get a byte.
我保证你会得到一个字节。
What will that byte be?
该字节是什么？
AUDIENCE: It's going to be modulo something.
听众：这将是模数。
Most significant--
最重要的 -
PROFESSOR: That's reasonable, right?
教授：那是合理的，对吗？
Modulo to 56 because that's what it can carry.
模数为56，因为它可以携带。
What about modulo?
模数呢？
What happens there if you get overflow?
如果您溢出该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: The same thing.
听众：同一件事。
It's just going to loop, right?
只是循环而已，对吗？
0?
0？
PROFESSOR: So if you do a modulo,
教授：所以，如果您做模，
this is going to be, at most, 255 right?
最多是255个吧？
If you do modulo 255, the remainder
如果对255做模，余数
is going to be between 0 and 254.
将在0到254之间。
Will that ever overflow byte?
那会溢出字节吗？
No overflow.
没有溢出。
No need to worry about it.
不用担心。
Word addition can overflow.
单词加法会溢出。
Subtraction can overflow.
减法可能溢出。
Multiplication doesn't overflow.
乘法不会溢出。
Division overflows, modulo doesn't.
除法溢出，取模不会。
AUDIENCE: What do you mean, like will it see the space confined?
听众：你是什么意思，就像它会看到空间受限吗？
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
It sees the space of the result.
它看到结果的空间。
Because here, if you're adding two words,
因为在这里，如果您要添加两个词，
the result exceeds the space of a word.
结果超出了一个单词的空间。
Which is what you get.
你得到的是什么。
AUDIENCE: Is it just in all cases it's just [INAUDIBLE].
听众：是不是在所有情况下都是[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Exactly.
教授：是的。
So the reason you have to deal with this weird system
所以您必须处理这个怪异系统的原因
is this is, pretty much, how Intel does their arithmetic.
这几乎就是英特尔如何进行算术运算的。
If you look at old school, 16-bit Intel processors,
如果您看看老式的16位Intel处理器，
you have registers and you have exactly these operations.
您有寄存器，并且您具有这些操作。
For newer processors, there are 32 bits, but then it's just,
对于较新的处理器，只有32位，但是
you write more F's on the board and you get the same thing.
你在板上写了更多的F，你会得到相同的结果。
AUDIENCE: Is it most significant bit, or most significant byte?
听众：是最高有效位还是最高有效字节？
PROFESSOR: Most significant byte.
教授：最高有效字节。
On a real processor, you have registers
在真实的处理器上，您有寄存器
that are the size of a word and then
那是一个字的大小，然后
you can pull out the bytes in constant time.
您可以在固定时间内提取字节。
What constant do we have?
我们有什么常数？
These are the operations.
这些是操作。
What constants do we have?
我们有什么常数？
Only two constants, 0 and 1.
只有两个常数0和1。
What if you want to get something bigger?
如果您想要更大的东西怎么办？
What if you want to get 2?
如果您想得到2怎么办？
How do you get 2?
你怎么得到2？
AUDIENCE: Two 1's?
听众：两个1？
1 plus 1?
1加1？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
What if you want to get this number?
如果您想获得这个号码怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Do that several times?
听众：做几次？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
PROFESSOR: It's kind of painful to type,
教授：打字有点痛苦，
even if you copy paste.
即使您复制粘贴。
There's a method on Word called from-bytes.
Word上有一种称为“从字节”的方法。
And it takes an M, S, B and an L, S, B
它需要一个M，S，B和一个L，S，B
and it gives you a word.
它给你一个字。
So what would I give it?
那我该怎么办呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Let's give it a 1 and let's give it a 0.
教授：我们给它一个1，然后给它一个0。
So this will get 1, 0, 0 and then minus 1.
所以这将得到1，0，0然后减1。
Yes?
是？
OK.
好。
Intel is pretty nice about constants,
英特尔对常量非常好，
but some other processors aren't.
但是其他一些处理器不是。
So I figured, why not let's get you acquainted
所以我想，为什么不让你结识
to these kind of tricks, to too.
这些技巧，也是如此。
Let's make the PSETS more interesting.
让我们使PSET更有趣。
All right, so any questions on this fake processor
好吧，所以关于这个假处理器的任何问题
that you have to code for?
你必须编码？
AUDIENCE: Can you explain the last one again?
听众：你能再解释一遍吗？
PROFESSOR: Here?
教授：这吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, Word from-bytes.
听众：是的，字从字节开始。
PROFESSOR: So in Word from-bytes a word is 2 bytes.
教授：所以在Word中，从字节开始，一个单词是2个字节。
One next to the other.
一个接一个。
It gives you the first byte, and gives you the second byte.
它给您第一个字节，并给您第二个字节。
In this case, the first byte is 1.
在这种情况下，第一个字节为1。
The second byte is 0.
第二个字节为0。
Right?
对？
So 2 bytes.
所以2个字节
A 1 and a 0.
A 1和0。
How do you write this in hex?
你怎么用十六进制写这个？
1, 0, 0.
1 0 0
One byte, second byte.
一个字节，第二个字节。
And then I subtract 1 and I get this.
然后我减去1，得到这个。
While I erase the board, I want you guys
我擦除董事会时，我希望你们
to think of graph questions because this
想图问题，因为这
is the other topic we're looking at today.
是我们今天要讨论的另一个主题。
What was unclear about the lecture?
讲座尚不清楚吗？
What is unclear about graphs in general?
一般来说，关于图有哪些不清楚的地方？
Do guys remember the handshaking lemma?
你们还记得握手引理吗？
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
How do you prove it?
你如何证明呢？
Things of that sort.
那种事情。
What do you guys want to cover today?
你们今天想讲什么？
AUDIENCE: Handshaking, that's the thing where
听众：握手，就是这样
you have a bunch nodes and they're all connected,
你有一堆节点，它们都连接在一起，
like they're all in a closed graph, that the number of edges
就像它们都在一个封闭图中一样，边的数量
is equal to twice the number of vertices?
等于顶点数量的两倍？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: That's all it is, right?
听众：仅此而已，对吧？
PROFESSOR: The number of vertices?
教授：顶点数？
No.
没有。
AUDIENCE: The number of handshakes
听众：握手次数
that occurred are twice the number of edges.
发生的次数是边缘数量的两倍。
You said the number of vertices, wait--
您说的是顶点数，等等-
PROFESSOR: No, vertices and edges are not related in here.
教授：不，此处的顶点和边不相关。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, think of a triangle, right?
听众：是的，想到一个三角形，对吗？
That's three edges, three vertices.
那是三个边缘，三个顶点。
Which is like not two times, which is what you said.
这不是两次，而是您所说的。
It's the number of degrees is twice the number of edges.
它的度数是边数的两倍。
That's what I was thinking of then.
那就是我当时的想法。
PROFESSOR: All right, so let's start with simple stuff.
教授：好的，让我们从简单的内容开始。
What's a graph?
什么是图？
AUDIENCE: Nodes and edges?
听众：节点和边缘？
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
Fancy word for nodes?
花哨的节点词？
AUDIENCE: Vertex.
听众：顶点。
PROFESSOR: Vertex.
教授：顶点。
Vertices and edges.
顶点和边缘。
How do I draw vertices?
如何绘制顶点？
How do I draw edges?
如何绘制边缘？
AUDIENCE: Circles and lines.
听众：圆和直线。
PROFESSOR: Circles and lines.
教授：圆和直线。
AUDIENCE: 0's and 1's.
受众：0和1。
Possibly arrows.
可能是箭头。
PROFESSOR: Possibly arrows.
教授：可能是箭头。
I like that.
我喜欢。
You want to get fancy.
你想花哨。
[LAUGHTER}
[笑声}
PROFESSOR: When do I draw an edge as a line?
教授：我何时画一条边线？
When do I draw it as an arrow?
什么时候画成箭头？
AUDIENCE: Directed under.
听众：指挥下。
PROFESSOR: Which one's which?
教授：哪个？
AUDIENCE: Directed as an arrow.
听众：指向箭头。
Character number.
字符编号。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
Let's draw this graph here.
让我们在这里画图。
Yeah, looks like a pretty boring graph.
是的，看起来像一个无聊的图表。
Is this graph connected or not?
此图是否已连接？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: What's a connected graph?
教授：什么是关联图？
AUDIENCE: I think that we can get
听众：我认为我们可以得到
to any other node following some path.
到某个路径之后的任何其他节点。
PROFESSOR: There's a path from any to any other node.
教授：从任何节点到任何其他节点都有一条路径。
How do I make this unconnected using
我如何使用
the least amount of effort?
最少的努力？
It's a bit of a trick question.
这是一个技巧问题。
Any guess is fine.
任何猜测都可以。
AUDIENCE: What was the question again?
听众：再问什么？
PROFESSOR: How do I make this unconnected
教授：我该如何断开连接
using the least amount of effort on my behalf?
代表我用最少的精力？
AUDIENCE: Just add a node?
听众：只是添加一个节点？
PROFESSOR: I heard you move pages.
教授：我听说你在移动页面。
I don't like you racing because I don't like the-- So
我不喜欢你赛车，因为我不喜欢
I like that answer out of the two I heard.
我喜欢听到的两个答案。
Now it's not a connected graph.
现在，它不是连接图。
How many connected component does it have?
它有多少个相连的组件？
Two and five.
二五
AUDIENCE: Or one connected component,
听众：或一个连接的组件，
but there are two components?
但是有两个组成部分？
PROFESSOR: OK, what's a connected component?
教授：好的，什么是连接的组件？
AUDIENCE: It's like in that part of the graph the neck follows
听众：就像在图的那部分
the prognito beacon and puts them in two parts [INAUDIBLE]
prognito信标并将其分为两部分[听不清]
two connected components--
两个连接的组件-
PROFESSOR: So, a connected component
教授：所以，一个连接的组件
is a bunch of vertices such that you can get from one vertex
是一堆顶点，因此您可以从一个顶点获得
to all the other vertices.
到所有其他顶点。
If the graph is undirected, that's
如果图形是无向的，那就是
true for any vertex in the set.
对集合中的任何顶点为true。
We also want the sets to be maximal
我们还希望集合最大
because, if we say this is a connected component,
因为，如果我们说这是一个连接的组件，
it's not very useful.
这不是很有用。
Noticing that this whole thing is a connected component
注意到这整个东西是一个连接的组件
is useful.
是有用的。
So this is one component.
因此，这是一个组成部分。
This is the other component.
这是另一个组件。
Make sense?
说得通？
So, we have the world.
因此，我们拥有世界。
We have cities.
我们有城市。
You can bike from a city to another city and that's it.
您可以从一个城市骑自行车到另一个城市，仅此而已。
No other a route of transportation.
没有其他运输路线。
How many connected components?
有多少个连接的组件？
AUDIENCE: Seven?
听众：七个？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Roughly seven.
大约七个。
Why?
为什么？
OK, so it only seven?
好吧，所以只有七个？
AUDIENCE: Seven continents?
听众：七大洲？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Let's say roughly seven.
大概是七个。
So this is what I wanted.
这就是我想要的。
I wanted some thinking.
我想想一想。
If you try to get from a continent to another continent,
如果您尝试从一个大陆到达另一个大陆，
presumably you'd go through some patch of sea.
大概你会经历一些海。
Otherwise, why are they calling them continents?
否则，他们为什么称它们为大洲？
Does anyone want to give out another answer?
有人想给出另一个答案吗？
I asked this in the previous section
我在上一节中问过
and some people there give me some very precise answers
有些人给我一些非常准确的答案
that are not continents.
那不是大洲。
This is what I had in mind, by the way.
顺便说一下，这就是我的想法。
As far as I'm concerned, this is a good answer.
就我而言，这是一个很好的答案。
Come on guys, world.
来吧，伙计们，世界。
Two things, islands and Europe and Asia are connected,
岛屿与欧洲和亚洲这两个方面相连，
so you can go from one to the other.
这样您就可以从一个转到另一个。
They're weird.
他们很奇怪。
Why are they separate continents?
他们为什么分开大洲？
I have no idea.
我不知道。
The geography people might--
地理人士可能-
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: You roll mountains?
听众：你滚山吗？
PROFESSOR: OK, so it would be a pain bike through them,
教授：好的，那将是一辆穿越他们的痛苦自行车，
but presumably you can.
但大概可以。
If you have a robot that doesn't get tired or something
如果您的机器人不疲劳或其他原因
you can bike.
你可以骑自行车。
AUDIENCE: It doesn't mind falling off cliffs.
听众：不介意从悬崖上掉下来。
PROFESSOR: The answer, depending on my geography,
教授：答案取决于我的地理位置，
we know is somewhere between 7 and 10,000,
我们知道大约在7到10,000之间
or whatever the number of islands is.
或任何岛屿数目。
There are a lot of tiny island somewhere, right?
那里有很多小岛，对不对？
Anyways, between seven and a big number.
无论如何，介于七个和大量之间。
These are connected components in the world.
这些是世界上相互连接的组件。
What's the degree of A?
A的度数是多少？
2.
2。
What's the degree of the D?
D的度数是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Very good.
教授：非常好。
Let's make this.
让我们做这个。
The degrees of F, G, H are 2, 2, 2.
F，G，H的度数分别为2、2、2。
The degree of C is 2.
C的度数是2。
The degree of B is?
B度是多少？
AUDIENCE: --2.
听众：--2。
PROFESSOR: Thank you.
教授：谢谢。
And the degree of E is?
E的度数是多少？
AUDIENCE: 2.
听众：2。
PROFESSOR: If you add up all these numbers together what
教授：如果把所有这些数字加起来
you get?
你得到？
18.
18岁
I can't do math, so I couldn't possibly
我不会做数学，所以我不可能
have added all these numbers together, right?
把所有这些数字加在一起，对吗？
I used something else.
我用了别的东西。
How many edges do I have in the graph?
图中有多少条边？
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、9
Do you see your connection here?
你在这里看到你的联系吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: This is the handshaking lemma.
教授：这是握手引理。
That's all there is to it.
这里的所有都是它的。
So if you look at the degrees of a node
所以，如果你看一个节点的度数
each edge adds one to two degrees.
每个边缘加一到两个度。
For instance, this edge adds one to C's degree
例如，这条边向C的度数加1
and adds one to D's degree.
并在D的学位上加一。
If you're a math person and you write this up,
如果您是数学家，并且将其写下来，
you have to write sums.
你必须写总和。
You have big sums using intimidating notation,
您使用吓人的符号赚了很多钱，
so it's not as obvious.
所以不是很明显
But this is really all there is to it.
但这实际上就是全部。
Each edge contributes one to two nodes degrees.
每个边贡献一到两个节点的度数。
If you add up all the degrees, you're
如果将所有学位加起来，
going to get to times the number of edges.
将要乘以边缘数。
So far so good?
到现在为止还挺好？
What if we have directed graphs?
如果我们有向图怎么办？
What if I had this?
如果我有这个怎么办？
A, B, C, D, E, F. What is the degree of A?
A，B，C，D，E，F。A的度数是多少？
AUDIENCE: 2?
听众：2？
PROFESSOR: Not quite.
教授：不完全是。
Sorry, that was trick question.
抱歉，这是技巧问题。
A doesn't have a degree.
A没有学位。
If you have directed graphs, you don't have degrees.
如果有向图，则没有度数。
You have in degrees and out degrees.
您有度数和度数。
Now that I've said that you have no idea, right?
现在，我说过你不知道，对不对？
What's the out degree of A?
A的出局程度是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Sometimes this is known as the degree of edges.
教授：有时这称为边缘度。
This is 2.
这是2
What's the in degree of A?
A的度数是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So A has two edges going out, 0 edges going in.
教授：所以A有两个边出，0个边入。
How about D?
D呢？
What's the out degree of D?
D的输出度是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Come on guys.
教授：伙计们。
Don't scare me. (LAUGHS) What's the in degree of D?
别吓我（笑）D的度数是多少？
AUDIENCE: 2?
听众：2？
PROFESSOR: 2, very good.
教授：2，很好。
PROFESSOR: So what's the equivalent
教授：那等于什么
of the handshaking lemma on oriented graphs?
图上握手引理的概念？
AUDIENCE: The sum of the in degrees and out degrees?
听众：进度和出度的总和？
PROFESSOR: OK, what about them?
教授：好的，他们呢？
AUDIENCE: They're equal to twice the number of vertices?
听众：它们等于顶点数量的两倍吗？
PROFESSOR: Not quite.
教授：不完全是。
They're equal to?
他们等于？
You had 80 percent of the answer.
您有80％的答案。
AUDIENCE: Oh. (LAUGHS)
听众：哦。 （笑声）
PROFESSOR: So the sum of the in degrees and the sum of the out
教授：所以度数的总和与度数的总和
degrees.
度。
AUDIENCE: So add them up?
听众：那么加起来？
PROFESSOR: If you add them up, you
教授：如果将它们加起来，
will get two times the number of edges.
将获得两倍的边缘数量。
That is correct.
那是对的。
But, I want something more--
但是，我想要更多……
AUDIENCE: They equal each other?
听众：他们彼此平等吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
This is cooler, right?
这很酷吧？
So why is that?
那为什么呢？
Does anyone see why that's the case?
有人知道为什么会这样吗？
Each edge-- Come on, guys.
每个边缘-来吧，伙计们。
So what does each edge do?
那么每个边缘做什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So if I look at this edge here,
教授：所以，如果我在这里看这个优势，
this edge is going to contribute 1 to B's out degree,
这个边缘将为B的出场率贡献1，
and 1 to D's in degree.
程度为1到D。
Each edge contributes 1 to an out degree
每个边缘贡献1的程度
and 1 to an in degree.
和1度。
That means that total sum of out degrees
这意味着出学位的总和
equals the total sum of in degrees.
等于度的总和。
Both of them are E and they combined to E. Sorry,
他们两个都是E，他们合并为E。对不起，
eyed I don't know why that didn't click to me right away.
眼睛，我不知道为什么没有立刻点击我。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: The intuition behind this
教授：这背后的直觉
is, that for every node, if you take an edge
是，对于每个节点，如果您占据优势
you're going to get somewhere else.
您将到达其他地方。
If the sum of the out degrees was bigger,
如果出学位的总和更大，
then you have a black hole somewhere.
那你在某个地方有一个黑洞
If you go on an edge you don't come back.
如果你走在边缘，你就不会回来。
Same four in degrees.
同样的四度。
OK, how do we represent graphs?
好，我们如何表示图？
AUDIENCE: I think we just did.
听众：我认为我们刚刚做到了。
PROFESSOR: Sure, if you're drawing them
教授：当然，如果您要绘制它们
on the board that's what you do, but if you're
在董事会上，这就是您要做的，但是如果您是
in Python what do you do?
在Python中做什么？
AUDIENCE: You can have a link list.
听众：您可以有一个链接列表。
PROFESSOR: Of?
教授：是的？
AUDIENCE: Of each node having its neighbors linked with.
听众：与每个邻居链接的节点。
PROFESSOR: OK, so I have one big link list?
教授：好的，所以我有一个很大的链接列表？
Or how does this work?
或如何运作？
AUDIENCE: You'd have a starting point of some sort.
听众：您会有某种起点。
A starting node.
起始节点。
Then from that node you can have its neighbors connected to it.
然后，可以从该节点连接其邻居。
So it was a link list , I guess.
我想这是一个链接列表。
PROFESSOR: I wasn't precise.
教授：我并不精确。
That is not trivial to build.
构建起来并不容易。
By the time we build that we're done with this recitation.
到我们构建时，我们已经完成了这一背诵。
What do you get is the vertices and the edges.
您得到的是顶点和边缘。
We want an easier representation that just looks at the vertices
我们想要一个更简单的表示，只看顶点
and build something, then looks at the edges
建造东西，然后看边缘
and builds something.
并建立一些东西。
AUDIENCE: You could have a table of values.
听众：您可以有一个值表。
Like, A has these neighbors-- a dictionary.
像，A有这些邻居-字典。
PROFESSOR: Let's go for that.
教授：我们去吧。
So we have a dictionary.
因此，我们有一本字典。
For each vertex you have the list
对于每个顶点，您都有列表
of vertices that are connected to it.
连接到它的顶点。
What's the list for A?
A的清单是什么？
AUDIENCE: B and C?
听众：B和C？
PROFESSOR: OK, what's the list for B?
教授：好的，B的清单是什么？
AUDIENCE: A, D, and E.
听众：A，D和E。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
For Python this would be a dictionary, right?
对于Python，这将是字典，对吗？
So how much total space does this take?
那么这需要多少总空间？
AUDIENCE: The number of nodes?
听众：节点数？
PROFESSOR: The number of--
教授：-
AUDIENCE: --nodes.
听众：--nodes。
Well, then there's also the space you made for the list,
好吧，那还有您为清单预留的空间，
though.
虽然。
PROFESSOR: If these were actual slots in an array--
教授：如果这些是阵列中的实际插槽，
so this would be an array-- I would have the number of nodes.
所以这将是一个数组-我将拥有节点数。
You're giving away the answer to my next question.
您正在放弃我的下一个问题的答案。
So I have these slots here.
所以我在这里有这些插槽。
This would be an array.
这将是一个数组。
It's order V just to store this.
V只是为了存储它。
The thing in Python is that have these dictionaries that
Python中的问题是具有这些字典
are fancy hashes where they grow as you need them.
是花哨的哈希，它们会在您需要的地方增长。
For example, you have 10,000 vertices
例如，您有10,000个顶点
but you don't have any edge.
但是你没有任何优势。
Your dictionary size is going to be order 1 because it only
您的字典大小将为1，因为它仅
grows as you add edges to it.
随着您向其添加边缘而增加。
So this is assuming that I don't store empty lists.
因此，这是假设我不存储空列表。
If I have a stray node here, if I
如果我在这里有一个杂散的节点
have a node I-- say this is I-- if I don't store anything,
我有一个节点-说这是我-如果我什么都不存储，
I don't have to pay for it.
我不必为此付费。
If I store an empty list here, then I have to pay for it.
如果我在此处存储一个空列表，则必须付费。
There is an order V component that you mentioned.
您提到了V阶分量。
AUDIENCE: Let's say, if there's a graph there,
听众：假设有一张图表，
everything is not connected so there are a bunch of words
一切都没有连接，所以有一堆字
instead.
代替。
Then in that case it would be order V, right?
那样的话就是五阶吧？
PROFESSOR: It's order V if we store empty lists
教授：如果我们存储空列表，则为订单V
for the nodes that don't have edges.
对于没有边的节点。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
And if none of the nodes have edges,
如果所有节点都没有边缘，
they're all unconnected--
他们都没有连接-
PROFESSOR: On the other hand, if I don't store anything
教授：另一方面，如果我什么都不存储
for the nodes that don't have edges, it's order 1.
对于没有边的节点，顺序为1。
AUDIENCE: If you get no edges do we do an empty list
观众：如果您没有优势，我们会做一个空清单
or do we not store it?
还是我们不存储它？
PROFESSOR: Depends on what you want.
教授：取决于您想要什么。
So if we store empty lists you're
因此，如果我们存储空列表，
going to have an order V cost here.
在这里要有一个订单V成本。
But your code is going to be simpler, presumably,
但是，您的代码可能会更简单，
because you don't have to check if something
因为您不必检查是否有东西
is or isn't in the dictionary.
字典中是否存在。
How about this stuff?
那东西呢？
What's the total size of this stuff here?
这个东西的总大小是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Order E. How many elements do I have in here in total?
订单E。我总共有多少个元素？
In this thing here.
在这件事上。
So what's the sum of the length of the lists?
那么，列表长度的总和是多少？
AUDIENCE: Average value of E times the number of vertices?
听众：E的平均值乘以顶点数？
PROFESSOR: Let's go over something else.
教授：让我们再谈一谈。
AUDIENCE: The degree--
听众：学位-
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
That's what I wanted to hear.
那就是我想听到的。
A lists its neighbors, right?
A列出了邻居，对不对？
The number of neighbors that A has is the degree of A. B
A拥有的邻居数是A的度数。
lists its neighbors, so this is the degree of B.
列出其邻居，所以这是B级。
If you sum up over all of them, what is the sum of all the
如果将它们全部加起来，那么所有
agrees in the graph?
在图中同意吗？
AUDIENCE: 2, E.
听众：2，E。
PROFESSOR: 2, E. We learned about this, right?
教授：2，E。我们了解到了，对吗？
The handshaking lemma, 2, E. So what
握手引理2，E。那又怎样
is the total cost for storing this data structure?
存储此数据结构的总成本是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So V plus E, assuming empty lists.
教授：所以V加E，假设有空列表。
Let's look at another data structure
让我们看看另一个数据结构
for storing things in a graph.
用于在图中存储事物。
So instead of using lists, let's use a matrix.
因此，我们不使用列表，而使用矩阵。
A, B, C, D, E on top, and A, B, C, D, E on the left.
顶部是A，B，C，D，E，左侧是A，B，C，D，E。
Let's pretend our graph is just that component over there.
让我们假装我们的图形就是那边的那个组件。
Otherwise, it just gets big and there's no extraneous site.
否则，它会变得很大，并且没有多余的站点。
Does anyone know how this is called?
有人知道这叫什么吗？
If I put numbers here, does anyone
如果我把数字放在这里，有人吗
know what this is called?
知道这叫什么吗？
AUDIENCE: Is that a matrix?
听众：这是矩阵吗？
PROFESSOR: There's a fancy name for it.
教授：有个花哨的名字。
It ends with matrix.
它以矩阵结尾。
OK.
好。
I don't think we taught it to you, so don't worry.
我认为我们没有教给您，所以不用担心。
The fancy name is maybe it's misspelled, but something
花式的名称可能是拼写错误的，但有些东西
that looks and sounds like this., adjacency matrix.
看起来和听起来像这样，邻接矩阵。
Misspelled?
拼错了吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: I hope someone will help me.
教授：我希望有人能帮助我。
OK so if this is an adjacency matrix,
好的，如果这是一个邻接矩阵，
what should this element between B and A tell me?
B和A之间的这个元素应该告诉我什么？
If it's an adjacency matrix, it better
如果是邻接矩阵，那就更好了
tell me if they're adjacent.
告诉我他们是否相邻。
They're adjacent if they have an edge between them.
如果它们之间有边，它们就是相邻的。
For A and B, what does it happen to be?
对于A和B，这是怎么回事？
AUDIENCE: One?
听众：一个？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
A and A?
A和A？
What do we do?
我们做什么？
AUDIENCE: What with 1?
听众：1代表什么？
It's adjacent to itself.
它与自己相邻。
PROFESSOR: What's easier for the algorithm
教授：该算法更容易
that you're trying to implement?
您正在尝试实施？
AUDIENCE: 1?
听众：1？
PROFESSOR: So it doesn't really matter.
教授：所以这并不重要。
We use 1's most of the time, but sometimes it's
我们大多数时候使用1，但有时
easier to use a 0.
更容易使用0。
AUDIENCE: Then you can get to A from A, right?
听众：然后您可以从A到达A，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So that's why you'd use a 1.
这就是为什么要使用1。
Sometimes, though, you don't want to in code.
但是有时候，您不想编写代码。
So someone dictate this to me.
所以有人命令我。
Or, everyone dictate this to me so I know it makes sense.
或者，每个人都对我说这句话，所以我知道这是有道理的。
A and C, is there an edge between them?
A和C之间是否有优势？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: What do I write?
教授：我怎么写？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: A and D?
教授：A和D？
A and E?
A和E？
AUDIENCE: 0.
听众：0。
PROFESSOR: B, A?
教授：B，A？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: B, C?
教授：B，C？
AUDIENCE: 0.
听众：0。
PROFESSOR: B, D?
教授：B，D？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: The E?
教授：E？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
C, A?
C，A？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: C, B?
教授：C，B？
AUDIENCE: 2.
听众：2。
PROFESSOR: C, D?
教授：C，D？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: C, E?
教授：C，E？
AUDIENCE: 0.
听众：0。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
Now I'm going to use the bits you
现在我要用你的零碎
gave me to come to get this.
给我来拿这个。
Let's see if I can do it correctly.
让我们看看我是否可以正确地做到这一点。
And D?
和D？
I'm not looking at the graph, by the way, I'm trusting you.
顺便说一句，我不是在看图表，而是在相信您。
So you better give me the right answer.
所以你最好给我正确的答案。
D?
D吗
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: How many 1's do I have in this?
教授：我有几个1？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: To see if you guys are thinking.
教授：看看你们是否在想。
AUDIENCE: 2, E? [INAUDIBLE].
听众：2，E？ [听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Each edge contributes to two 1's, right?
教授：每个边都贡献两个1，对吗？
And that accounts for most of the 1's.
这占了大多数的1。
AUDIENCE: O plus V.
听众：O加V。
PROFESSOR: So this is how many 1's I have.
教授：这就是我有1个。
How many 0's do I have?
我有几个0？
AUDIENCE: V squared minus 2, E plus V?
听众：V平方减去2，E加V？
PROFESSOR: This is a non-boring way
教授：这是一种无聊的方式
of asking how many elements I have in this matrix.
问我在这个矩阵中有多少个元素。
This is what I was looking for.
这就是我想要的。
So V columns, right?
那么V列吧？
Zeros V squared's total elements.
零位V平方的总元素。
How much memory do I need to store this?
我需要多少存储空间？
AUDIENCE: V squared.
听众：V平方。
PROFESSOR: V squared. what?
教授：V平方。什么？
If I want to store it as compactly as possible?
是否要尽可能紧凑地存储？
I want to pack these as tight as I can.
我想尽可能地收紧它们。
AUDIENCE: You mean you need the entire array arranged?
听众：您的意思是您需要排列整个阵列吗？
PROFESSOR: Yes, so what do I store?
教授：是的，那我应该存储什么？
V squared what?
V平方什么？
AUDIENCE: Oh, you mean units.
听众：哦，你的意思是单位。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
What's the unit?
什么单位
AUDIENCE: 1 bit?
听众：1位？
PROFESSOR: All right!
教授：好的！
So V squared bits Whereas, this is V plus E words
因此，V个平方位是V加E字
because you have to store pointers everywhere here.
因为您必须将指针存储在此处的所有位置。
So sometimes if your graph is really dense
所以有时候如果你的图真的很密集
you might prefer this representation.
您可能更喜欢这种表示形式。
Let me see, how much do I have?
让我看看，我有多少？
Oh, plenty of time.
哦，时间充裕。
Who remembers breadth-first search?
谁记得广度优先搜索？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Basically you just start at some node
听众：基本上，您只是从某个节点开始
and you check all its neighbors, and check all those neighbors.
然后检查所有邻居，然后检查所有这些邻居。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
In breadth-first search we have a graph.
在广度优先搜索中，我们有一个图。
What did I draw there?
我在那里画了什么？
A. B, E. So suppose this is our graph.
A. B，E.因此，假设这是我们的图形。
And I do a breadth-first search starting at A.
我从A开始进行广度优先的搜索。
How does that work?
这是如何运作的？
I started with the list of the nodes that I'm going to visit.
我从要访问的节点列表开始。
I initialization it with A because this is the only node
我用A初始化它，因为这是唯一的节点
that I know about.
我知道的
What happens next?
接下来发生什么？
AUDIENCE: It goes with B and C.
听众：与B和C并存。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So I take out of the list the first thing that I can.
因此，我将第一件事从清单中删除。
This is my current node.
这是我当前的节点。
You said I visit B and C because they're the neighbors.
你说我拜访B和C是因为他们是邻居。
Right.
对。
I took A out of the list.
我从列表中删除了A。
A was definitely visited.
肯定有人来过。
And I'm visiting B and C. What do I do when I visit them?
我正在访问B和C。访问B和C时该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Put them in the list.
听众：将它们放在列表中。
PROFESSOR: Put them in the list.
教授：将它们放在列表中。
This means I discovered them and I'm going to visit the later.
这意味着我发现了它们，以后我将去参观。
So I discovered them and I know of their existence.
因此我发现了它们，并且知道了它们的存在。
What happens next?
接下来发生什么？
AUDIENCE: Check if B is what you want.
听众：检查B是否是您想要的。
PROFESSOR: So B gets out of the list, and what do I do?
教授：所以B不在名单上，我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Discover it's neighbors.
听众：发现它的邻居。
PROFESSOR: All right, so its neighborhoods
教授：好的，所以附近
are A, B, and E. What Now?
是A，B和E。现在怎么办？
AUDIENCE: If they haven't already
听众：如果他们还没有
been on that list then add a [INAUDIBLE].
在该列表中，然后添加[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: A was already visited.
教授：已经参观过。
D and E weren't.
D和E不是。
D and E, then what happens?
D和E，然后会发生什么？
AUDIENCE: Then you check C's neighbors.
听众：然后您检查C的邻居。
PROFESSOR: Any neighbor's that I haven't seen?
教授：我没见过邻居吗？
Nope.
不。
Then?
然后？
AUDIENCE: D?
听众：D？
AUDIENCE: D and?
听众：D和？
AUDIENCE: E.
听众：E.
PROFESSOR:OK.
教授：好的。
And then?
接着？
PROFESSOR: I guess you could go to F,
教授：我想你可以去F
but it's not connected to anything.
但没有连接任何东西。
But how did you get A then, right?
但是你是怎么得到A的呢？
PROFESSOR: So A is the first node.
教授：所以A是第一个节点。
I started with A because I said I'm
我从A开始，因为我说我
doing a breadth-first search starting from A.
从A开始进行广度优先搜索。
So BFS starts from somewhere.
因此，BFS从某个地方开始。
A BFS has a source.
BFS有一个源。
We'll see why that matters in a bit.
我们将稍等一下。
So you ever get to see F?
所以你曾经见过F吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: Nope.
教授：不。
So if I start at A what are the nodes that I visit
因此，如果我从A开始，我访问的节点是什么
and what are the nodes that I don't visit?
我不访问哪些节点？
AUDIENCE: Well you visit all the ones in the connected graph.
听众：好吧，您访问了所连接图中的所有对象。
PROFESSOR: All right, in the connected component.
教授：好的，在连接的组件中。
So the whole graph can be connected or not connected.
因此，整个图可以连接或不连接。
The nodes that I visit are the nodes
我访问的节点是节点
in A's connected component because, by definition, those
在A的连接组件中，因为根据定义，
are the nodes that I can reach from A.
是我可以从A到达的节点。
If I have many kind of the components
如果我有很多种类的组件
and I use BFS starting from one node,
我从一个节点开始使用BFS，
I might not visit the entire graph.
我可能不会访问整个图。
How do I keep track of what node that I've discovered
我如何跟踪发现的节点
and haven't discovered?
还没发现？
What data structure do I use for these smiley faces?
这些笑脸应该使用什么数据结构？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR:So for the smiley faces.
教授：所以笑脸。
For this thing I probably want a queue.
为此，我可能需要排队。
We'd teach you something simpler,
我们会教你一些简单的方法，
but most of the time when you write the code you
但是在大多数情况下，当您编写代码时，
actually use queue.
实际使用队列。
What do I want for the smiley faces?
我想要什么笑脸？
When I pull a node out, say I pulled out B,
当我拉出节点时，说我拉出了B，
and I see A, D, E, I want to know that I visited A
我看到A，D，E，我想知道我去过A
and I didn't visit the D and E. You guys remember
我没有去D和E。你们还记得
that we didn't visit D and E, right, by the time we got to 2?
在到达2时我们还没有访问D和E，对吗？
OK.
好。
So I want to be able to check whether I visited a node
所以我想能够检查我是否访问过一个节点
or not really fast.
或不是真的很快。
What data structure should I use for the smileys?
笑脸应该使用什么数据结构？
AUDIENCE: A hash table.
受众：哈希表。
PROFESSOR: A has table.
教授：A有桌子。
Cool.
凉。
What's a hash table in Python?
什么是Python中的哈希表？
AUDIENCE: A dictionary.
听众：字典。
PROFESSOR: A dictionary.
教授：字典。
All right, so this is going to be a seen, which
好吧，这将是一个可见的
is a dictionary, and it maps vertices to maybe true.
是一个字典，它将顶点映射为true。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR:Yep.
教授：是的。
Python has a set, right?
Python有一套，对吧？
So you can use that.
因此您可以使用它。
The smileys needs to be some sort of a dictionary.
笑脸必须是某种字典。
So given that, and assuming that this
因此，假设
is a queue that we can extract and you
是我们可以提取的队列，您
can start from in constant time, what
可以从恒定的时间开始
is the running time of BFS?
是BFS的运行时间？
Let's make life easy.
让生活变得轻松。
Let's assume the graph is connected and let's assume just
让我们假设图是连通的，让我们假设
doesn't exist.
不存在。
BFS was the running time.
BFS是运行时间。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] visiting.
听众：[听不清]来访。
PROFESSOR: So you visit every node once,
教授：所以您一次访问每个节点，
so it's at least V. That's a start.
所以至少是V。这是一个开始。
Now what do you do when you visit the node?
现在，当您访问该节点时您会做什么？
AUDIENCE: Check out all the--
观众：查看所有-
PROFESSOR: All the neighbors, right?
教授：所有邻居，对吗？
Given the node, you have to go to the data structure
给定节点，您必须转到数据结构
that you have that's either this or this,
你拥有的就是这个或这个，
and you have to get a list of neighbors.
你必须得到邻居名单。
If I have this data structure, how fast
如果我有这个数据结构，多快
do I get a list of neighbors for a node?
如何获取节点的邻居列表？
AUDIENCE: Order of the degree?
听众：学位的顺序？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Order of the degree of the node.
节点度的顺序。
That's good.
那很好。
How about this data structure?
这个数据结构怎么样？
AUDIENCE: Same-- oh, no that's order of V.
听众：一样-哦，不，这是V的顺序。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So in this data structure, for example, C only
因此，在此数据结构中，例如，仅C
has two edges coming out of it.
有两个边缘出来。
But I have to go through the entire lining of the matrix
但是我必须遍历整个矩阵
to see where I have my 0's and where I have my 1's.
看看我的0在哪里，我的1在哪里。
In order to list the neighbors, here is straight up order V,
为了列出邻居，这是直接向上的顺序V，
whereas this is order of the degree of the node
而这是节点度数的顺序
that I'm looking for.
我在寻找。
So for this, where it's nice and simple, order of V,
因此，在这很简单的地方，V的阶数
what is the total running time?
总运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: Wait, because it's B plus B. Oh no, it's
听众：等等，因为它是B加B。哦，不，这是
the same one.
同一个。
PROFESSOR: So for each node I have to?
教授：那么对于每个节点我都必须？
AUDIENCE: V squared.
听众：V平方。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we're up to V squared already.
所以我们已经达到V平方了。
What else do we need to do?
我们还需要做什么？
Anything that they need to do on a node is order of V,
他们在节点上需要做的任何事情都是V的阶数，
so V squared is going to be the total running time.
因此V平方将是总运行时间。
That's it.
而已。
So if we use an adjacency matrix we
因此，如果我们使用邻接矩阵，
get order of V squared as the total running time.
将V的阶次平方作为总运行时间。
What about if we lists, what the running time?
如果我们列出该如何运行？
I'll give you a hint.
我会给你一个提示。
You have to use amortized analysis.
您必须使用摊销分析。
Shivers anyone?
怕谁？
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
We know it's order V because we're
我们知道它是V阶，因为
going to visit every node.
去拜访每个节点。
And you guys didn't see what I was going to write here.
你们没看到我要在这里写的内容。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
OK.
好。
So for every node I go through the neighbors
因此，对于每个节点，我都会穿越邻居
and I do something to them.
我为他们做点事。
Right?
对？
I check if they're in seen, if not then I
我检查他们是否在看，如果没有，我
add them to the list.
将它们添加到列表中。
So for every node the work is?
那么每个节点的工作是什么？
AUDIENCE: it's degrees.
听众：是度。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So if I look at all the nodes?
那么，如果我查看所有节点？
AUDIENCE: That's E.
听众：就是E。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
For every node I have to look at its neighbors
对于每个节点，我必须查看其邻居
and I have to see which neighbors are in seen.
我必须看看有哪些邻居。
For the neighbors that are not in seen
对于看不见的邻居
I have to add to my queue.
我必须添加到队列中。
Checking if a neighbor is in seen or not is order 1.
检查邻居是否在视线中。
Adding it to the queue is order 1.
将其添加到队列是订单1。
So the total work for a node is order
因此，节点的总工作量是订单
of neighbors because of the adjacency list, not matrix.
因为邻接表而不是矩阵。
If I look at the entire graph, here I
如果我看整个图，我在这里
can't do a local analysis like I did before.
不能像以前一样进行本地分析。
If I look at the entire graph and I look at all the nodes
如果我看整个图，我看所有节点
slash vertices, then the total work
斜线顶点，然后是总功
is the sum of their degrees.
是他们度数的总和。
For each node is degree.
对于每个节点都是度。
For total work, sum of the degrees.
对于总功，度的和。
And I have that nice handshaking lemma
我有一个很好的握手引理
that says that the sum of the degrees is 2,
那表示度数的总和是2
E. So order E. So total running time?
E.那么订购E.这样总的运行时间？
V plus E.
V加E。
OK, can I say that the running time is order E?
好，我可以说运行时间是E阶吗？
With no V's?
没有V吗？
AUDIENCE: No, because you have to look at every--
听众：不，因为您必须审视每个-
PROFESSOR: Is it?
教授：是吗？
AUDIENCE: V greater than [INAUDIBLE]
听众：V大于[听不清]
in case of not connected components?
如果未连接组件？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: It's possible that you could
听众：您可能会
have more vertices than edges--
顶点比边多-
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So it's possible that I have more vertices than edges.
因此，我的顶点比边缘多。
I agree with that, but I do anything to the vertices
我同意这一点，但是我对顶点做任何事情
that I haven't seen?
我没见过？
So this is subtle.
所以这很微妙。
The difference between this and this
这个和这个之间的区别
is a matter of how you implement everything.
与如何实现所有事情有关。
In CLRS they assume that the seen is an array.
在CLRS中，他们假定所见是数组。
So all of their nodes have numbers from 1 to V.
因此，它们的所有节点都有从1到V的数字。
So then they initialize an array, everything is false,
所以他们初始化了一个数组，一切都是假的，
and then they set the true elements.
然后他们设置了真正的元素。
In Python we can use a dictionary
在Python中，我们可以使用字典
and not initialize it with anything.
而不用任何东西初始化它。
So if you do it that way in Python and code carefully,
因此，如果您使用Python进行这种操作并仔细编写代码，
you can get to order E. The parts of the graph
您可以订购E。图表的各个部分
that you don't discover, you don't have to pay for them.
您不会发现的，您不必为它们付费。
If you look at CLRS code, it is definitely
如果您查看CLRS代码，那肯定是
V plus E. The difference between this and this
V加E。此与此之间的差异
depends on the code.
取决于代码。
What's the point of BFS, by the way?
顺便说一下，BFS的意义是什么？
Why do we care?
我们为什么在乎？
What does it give us?
它给我们带来什么？
AUDIENCE: The shortest word path.
听众：最短的单词路径。
PROFESSOR:The shortest path from point?
教授：到点的最短路径？
AUDIENCE: From your start to where you're going.
听众：从一开始到您要去的地方。
PROFESSOR:So it gives you the shortest path from the node
教授：因此，它为您提供了距节点最短的路径
that I'm starting the BFS from.
我从这里开始BFS。
So only from this node?
那么只能从这个节点开始吗？
If I start BFS at A it's going to give me
如果我从A开始BFS，它将给我
the length of the shortest path from A to which node?
从A到哪个节点的最短路径的长度？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: All the nodes?
教授：所有节点？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: All the nodes that are
教授：所有的节点
visited by BFS are reachable and we have a path from them.
BFS所访问的地方都是可以到达的，我们有一条通往之路。
How do you compute this distance?
您如何计算此距离？
Let's see, so what's the distance from A to A?
让我们看看，从A到A的距离是多少？
AUDIENCE: 0?
听众：0？
PROFESSOR: 0.
教授：0。
When I start from A and I see that its neighbors are B and C,
当我从A开始时，我发现它的邻居是B和C，
what's the distance from A to B and from A to C?
A到B以及A到C的距离是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Now I look at B. What's the distance between A and A?
现在我看一下B。A和A之间的距离是多少？
A is B's neighbor.
A是B的邻居。
AUDIENCE: With A and A?
听众：和A和A？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So I have three neighbors.
所以我有三个邻居。
B has three neighbors, A, D, and E.
B具有三个邻居A，D和E。
So I care about the distances between A and A, D, E. Distance
所以我在乎A与A，D，E之间的距离。
A, A, distance A, D, and distance A, E. This one is 0.
A，A，距离A，D和距离A，E。这是0。
How about the distances between A and D and A and E?
A和D之间以及A和E之间的距离如何？
They're 2.
他们是2岁
So the way I would compute these distances
所以我计算这些距离的方式
is that I start with A being 0.
是从A为0开始的
The distance from A to A is 0.
A到A的距离是0。
And then when I look at a node, when I discover the neighbors,
然后当我看着一个节点，当我发现邻居时，
all the neighbors that don't have smiley faces on them
所有没有笑脸的邻居
get the node's distance plus 1.
得到节点的距离加1。
You can get to them by getting in the current node
您可以通过进入当前节点来找到他们
and then traversing an edge.
然后穿越边缘。
When you do that it's important that you don't update
当您这样做时，请务必不要更新
the distances of the nodes that have smiley faces.
带有笑脸的节点的距离。
If you do, you're going to say that the distance from A to A
如果这样做，您会说从A到A的距离
is 2 and all hell breaks lose from there.
是2，所有的地狱突破都会从那里消失。
AUDIENCE: Wait, why would you say it would be 2?
听众：等等，你为什么要说是2？
PROFESSOR: If I forget the fact that it has a smiley face.
教授：如果我忘记了它有一张笑脸的事实。
So if I go through all these neighbors
所以如果我穿过所有这些邻居
and I say the distance from A to B
我说从A到B的距离
is one then the distance from A to all of B's neighbors
是A到B的所有邻居的距离
has to be 2.
必须为2。
That would be wrong.
那是错误的。
AUDIENCE: Wait, from A to all of--
听众：等等，从A到所有
PROFESSOR: B's neighbors.
教授：B的邻居。
AUDIENCE: From A to all of-- Oh, because A is one Of--
听众：从A到全部-哦，因为A是其中的一个-
PROFESSOR: B's neighbors.
教授：B的邻居。
AUDIENCE: Yeah OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: The smileys tell me which
教授：笑脸告诉我
vertices I've already seen and I've already,
我已经看到并且已经出现过的顶点
presumably computed distances for them.
大概计算出它们的距离。
We don't want to update those.
我们不想更新这些。
OK this is BFS in essence.
好的，这本质上是BFS。
One question.
一个问题。
Between Facebook and Twitter, which one's directed
在Facebook和Twitter之间，由某人指挥
and which one's undirected?
以及哪个是非定向的？
AUDIENCE: Facebook is undirected.
听众：Facebook是无向的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Facebook is undirected.
Facebook是无向的。
Why is it undirected?
为什么是无向的？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: When you follow someone they don't necessarily
听众：当您跟随某人时，他们不一定
follow you.
跟随你。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So this is Twitter, right?
这就是Twitter，对不对？
Twitter, directed because of follows.
Twitter，由于以下原因而被导演。
Has anyone used Facebook recently?
最近有没有人使用Facebook？
Did you guys see there's a new option?
你们看到新的选择了吗？
AUDIENCE: The little scroll bar on the side?
听众：侧面的小滚动条？
PROFESSOR: Subscribers.
教授：订户。
AUDIENCE: Oh, ya.
听众：哦，是的。
PROFESSOR: OK, so how do subscribers work?
教授：好的，订户如何工作？
AUDIENCE: You subscribe.
听众：您订阅。
It's like google plus.
就像谷歌加。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Directed are undirected?
定向是非定向的吗？
If I subscribe to you do you have to subscribe to me?
如果我订阅了您，您是否必须订阅我？
AUDIENCE: Directed.
听众：导演。
PROFESSOR: So which one is it?
教授：那是哪一个？
AUDIENCE: I guess Facebook is kind of directed now
观众：我想Facebook现在是导演
because you can unsubscribe from people.
因为您可以取消订阅人。
PROFESSOR: Is it?
教授：是吗？
So Facebook has two graphs in it.
因此，Facebook中有两个图表。
They happen to have the same vertices.
它们碰巧具有相同的顶点。
The people are the vertices in both graphs.
人物是两个图中的顶点。
But the friends relationship defines an undirected graph.
但是朋友关系定义了无向图。
The subscribers relationship defines a directed graph.
订户关系定义了有向图。
The graphs are completely different.
这些图完全不同。
And there are two graphs.
并且有两个图。
That's the right way to reason about them.
这是对它们进行推理的正确方法。
that's why it was slightly tricky.
这就是为什么它有些棘手。
Can someone think of a cool way to use BFS on Facebook?
有人可以想到在Facebook上使用BFS的好方法吗？
AUDIENCE: That's networks, right?
听众：那是网络，对吗？
Figuring out how many people are in the first degree
弄清楚有多少人在第一学位
or second degree.
或第二学位。
MySpace was really into that.
MySpace确实参与其中。
PROFESSOR: Lincoln also does that, right?
教授：林肯也这样做，对吗？
How many people are your friends?
你的朋友有几个？
How many people are your friend's friends?
您朋友的朋友有多少人？
So and so forth.
等等。
Now suppose you want to get to someone in Facebook
现在假设您想在Facebook上结识某人
and you don't know them directly.
而且您不直接认识他们。
They're not your friends.
他们不是你的朋友。
Presumably, you want to get to them
想必您想去找他们
through the minimum amount of effort.
通过最少的努力。
So you want to see do you have a friend that knows them?
所以你想看看你有没有一个认识他们的朋友？
If not, do you have a friend that
如果没有，你有没有一个朋友
knows a friend that knows them?
认识一个认识他们的朋友吗？
Do you have a friend that knows a friend that
你有认识一个朋友的朋友吗
knows a friend that knows them?
认识一个认识他们的朋友吗？
So and so forth.
等等。
So BFS will give you that minimum path.
因此，BFS将为您提供最小路径。
OK.
好。
do the graphs make sense?
这些图有意义吗？
So by the way, the BFS on Facebook
顺便说一下，Facebook上的BFS
is just the beginning of a ton of cool things
只是很多有趣事物的开始
you can with graph algorithms.
您可以使用图算法。